hey guys bre and tras here in this video
I'm going to teach you the modified um
deadlift kabell swing I don't know what
else to call it but basically uh when I
was um started giving heavy kabell
deadlifts to uh my clients I noticed the
the ones who activated their glutes the
best the better ones they would kind of
sink back and do like this modified
swing looking thing anyway I tried it
out and I felt more glute doing it this
way so I let them roll with it and I I
actually started kind of prescribing
this to some of them so here's what it
looks like instead of just
doing a regular dead look like
this um which by the way would have the
most hip extension torque here and the
least here so you're going to get good
strength in the flexed position but not
so much up top well they would start to
do it like this they come up and they
sink back and kind of come like
this so it looks like
this
so this way you get more even hip
extension torque throughout the
movement so it's a more well-rounded
glute
exercise but um it's also it's kind of
like a mix between a deadlift and a
swing so I like it a lot because if you
have a barbell and a light kle Bell you
can do you know heavy barbell deadlifts
and light kle Bell swings but if you
have a heavy kettle bell like this you
could do you know get them good at the
deadlifts then transition into that
modified um deadlift swing and then
finally into a full swing so
initially the first you know couple
months they might start off looking like
this you know and then their next couple
months might be like
this and then after a few months it's
more like
this
so um by the way this here is a 48 kg or
um 106 lb kettle bell by
Apollo so they sell these and these are
really good for personal trainers and
strength coaches to use with females or
with uh beginner males because it's
really easy to learn kind of like a a
trap bar deadlift but lets you go inside
so I hope these get more popular with
strength coaches and personal trainers
over time thanks for watching